<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Yumou Qiu&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Yumou Qiu&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19</title>
      <link>/covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Brief on COVID-19 Pandemic  March 3 2020
 March 5 2020
 March 12 2020
 March 15 2020
 March 19 2020
 April 23 2020
  Shiny Apps Estimation of Reproduction Number and Prediction for COVID-19 Epidemic
Vaccine effects The manuscript Real-World COVID-19 Vaccine Protection Rates against Infection in the Delta and Omicron Eras (by Zhu, Y., Gu, J., Qiu, Y. and Chen, S. X.) estimates the real-world protection rates of vaccination (VPRs) against the SARS-Cov-2 infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation</title>
      <link>/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presentation/</guid>
      <description>Conference invited  A Pipeline for Analyzing High-throughput Plant Phenotyping Data, invited talk at The Plant Phenomics webinar, May, 2021.
 Sharp Optimality for High Dimensional Covariance Testing, invited talk at CFE-CMStatistics 2020 (virtual), Dec, 2020.
 Sharp Optimality for High Dimensional Covariance Testing, invited talk at The ICSA 2020 Applied Statistics Symposium (virtual), Dec, 2020.
 Simple Plant Image Segmentation by Neural Network, invited talk at The Plant Phenome Journal (TPPJ) webinar, February, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication and manuscript</title>
      <link>/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/</guid>
      <description>Selected publication Statistical metholody
 Chen, S. X., Guo, B. and Qiu, Y. (2022). Global Test and Signal Identification for Two-sample Covariances via Multi-level Thresholding. Journal of Econometrics.
 Hu, H. and Qiu, Y. (2022). Inference for Nonparanormal Partial Correlation via Regularized Rank-based Nodewise Regression. Biometrics.
 Qiu, Y. and Zhou, X. H. (2021). Inference on Multi-level Brain Connectivities based on fMRI Data. The Journal of the American Statistical Association: Theory and Methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research interest</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description> High-dimensional data analysis&amp;ndash;methods and theories
 Inference on large covariance and precision matrices
 Causal inference
 Association studies for genotype and phenotype
 Computation and analysis pipeline for high-throughput phenotyping
 Epidemiological models for COVID-19
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>STAT 647: Advanced Multivariate Analysis, Spring 2021 (ISU). Theoretical course introducing both classical and high dimensional multivariate methods and their theories. The contents include multivariate random vectors and its distribution, dependence measures and copula, Wishart distribution, concentration Inequality, random matrix theory, Hotelling’s test, high-dimensional inference for mean and covariance, signal detection and identification.
 STAT 475 / 575: Introduction to Multivariate Data Analysis, Fall 2020, Fall 2021 (ISU). Statistical and graphical methods for analyzing multivariate data; organizing and summarizing analyses of multivariate data; principal components and factor analysis; classification; clustering; R statistical software package and the use of Rstudio to create reports (RMarkdown and GGplot).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>