<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Yumou Qiu&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Yumou Qiu&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19</title>
      <link>/covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Brief on COVID-19 Epidemic
 March 3 2020
 March 5 2020
 March 12 2020
 March 15 2020
 March 19 2020
 April 23 2020
  Estimation of Reproduction Number and Prediction for COVID-19 Epidemic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation</title>
      <link>/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presentation/</guid>
      <description>Conference invited  Optimal Thresholding Test for High Dimensional Covariance Matrices, invited talk at IMS-China International Conference on Statistics and Probability, Dalian, China, July, 2019.
 Estimating Multi-level Partial Correlation Graphs, invited talk at 2019 ICSA Applied Statistics Symposium, Raleigh, June 2019.
 Thresholding Inference for Covariance Learning, 2018 ICSA China Conference with the Focus on Data Science, Qingdao, China, July 2-5, 2018.
 Thresholding Inference for Covariance Learning, The 8th International Forum on Statistics, Renmin University of China, Beijing, China, July 1-2, 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication and manuscript</title>
      <link>/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/</guid>
      <description>Selected publication  Liang, Z., Qiu, Y. and Schnable, J. (2020). Genome-phenome Wide Association in Maize and Arabidopsis Identifies a Common Molecular and Evolutionary Signature. Molecular Plant. Code
 Adams, J., Qiu, Y., Xu, Y. and Schnable, J. (2020). Plant Segmentation by Deep Neural Nets. The Plant Phenome. Code
 Qiu, Y. and Liyanage, J. (2019). Threshold Selection for Covariance Estimation. Biometrics, 75 985-905. Code
 Chang, J., Qiu, Y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research interest</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description> Inference on large covariance and precision matrices
 High-dimensional statistical inference and applications in genetic analysis
 Statistical analysis for brain imaging
 Causal inference
 High-throughput plant phenotying
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Stat 347: Probability and Statistical Theory for Data Science, Fall 2019 (ISU). Topics include introduction to probability, random variables and distribution functions; sampling distributions; theory of estimation; theory of inference; use of R statistical package for simulation and data analysis.
 Stat 501: Multivariate Statistical Methods, Spring 2019 (ISU). Topics include multivariate normal distribution; simultaneous analysis of multiple responses; MANOVA; high dimensional regression; PCA; factor analysis; classification methods.
 DS 202: Data Acquisition and Data Exploratory Analysis, Fall 2018 (ISU).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>